Inventory of the American Association for Higher Education records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject file, 1978-2005; 126-129 (Box 126-129)
  - Academic careers, 1979-1981 (Folder 127)
  - Academic leadership, 1984 (Folder 127)
  - Academic strategy, 1982 (Folder 127)
  - American professoriate, 1982-1987 (Folder 127)
  - Academic compensation (Hansen study), 1984 (Folder 127)
  - Audio conferencing, 1983 (Folder 127)
  - Audio-workshop series, 1983-1984 (Folder 127)
  - Better information for student choice, 1978 (Folder 127)
  - Constituencies, 2002 (Folder 128: 1-2)
  - National Council for Higher Education, 1993 (Folder 128: 3)
  - National Council of Teachers of English, 1993 (Folder 128: 4)
  - National Council for History of Education, 1989-1990 (Folder 128: 5)
  - Pharmacy schools, 1992-1993 (Folder 128: 6)
  - Tomas Rivera, 1985 (Folder 128: 7)
  - Caucuses, 1993-2005 (Folder 128-129)
    - Black, 1993 (Folder 128: 8)
    - Hispanic, 1994-1995 (Folder 128: 9)
    - Membership development, 1993 (Folder 128: 10)
    - Membership, 1993-1994 (Folder 128: 11)
    - Caucus resolution, 1995 (Folder 128: 12)
    - General, 1993-1995 (Folder 128: 13)
    - AAHE research forum, 2000 (Folder 129: 1)
    - American Indian/Alaska Native, 2000 (Folder 129: 2)
    - Asian, 2003 (Folder 129: 3)
    - Meeting, 2004-2005 (Folder 129: 4)
    - Black, 2000-2003 (Folder 129: 5-6)
    - Constituency group information, 2004 (Folder 129: 7)
    - Membership, 1999 (Folder 129: 8)
    - Hispanic, 2004 (Folder 129: 9)
    - General, 2002 (Folder 129: 10)
- Publications, 1947-2005; 130-161 (Box 130-161: 10)
  Journals, monographs, newsletters, magazines, and reports published or edited by AAHE
  - AAHE Bulletin, 1982-1989 (Folder 130)
  - AAHE Bulletin bound volumes, 1982-1990 (Folder 131)
  - AAHE Bulletin, 1999-2002 (Folder 132)
  - Index to volumes of AAHE Bulletin, 1987-1990 (Folder 132)
    Includes one 3.5-inch floppy disk
  - AAHE Bulletin bound volumes, 1996-2000 (Folder 133)
  - AAHE Bulletin newsletters, 1978-1980 (Folder 133)
  - AAHE Bulletin bound volumes, 1994 September-1998 June (Folder 134)
  - AAHE Bulletin bound volumes, 1992 September-1994 June (Folder 135)
  - AAHE Bulletin newsletters, 1995-1997 (Folder 135)
  - AAHE Bulletin bound volumes, 1990 September-1992 June (Folder 136)
  - AAHE Bulletin, 1989-1993 (Folder 136)
  - Change: The Magazine of Higher Learning, 1974-1975, 2002-2005 (Folder 137)
  - Change: The Magazine of Higher Learning, 1976-1979 (Folder 138)
  - Change: The Magazine of Higher Learning, 1981-1984 (Folder 139)
  - Change: The Magazine of Higher Learning, 1983, 1999-2002 (Folder 140)
  - Change: The Magazine of Higher Learning, 1984-1990 (Folder 141)
  - Change: The Magazine of Higher Learning, 1991-1994 (Folder 142)
  - Change: The Magazine of Higher Learning, 1994-1996 (Folder 143)
  - Change: The Magazine of Higher Learning, 1994-1996 (Folder 144)
  - National Conference for Higher Education programs, 1970-1995 (Folder 144)
  - Change: The Magazine of Higher Learning, 1997-1999 (Folder 145)
    Also includes binder on membership studies, 1988
  - College and University Bulletin bound volumes, 1948-1968 (Folder 146)
  - College and University Bulletin, 1971-1978 (Folder 147)
  - Current Issues in Higher Education, vols. 1-2, 1947-1954 (Folder 148)
    Includes files relating to grant funding, 1994
  - Current Issues in Higher Education, vols. 3-5, 1955-1966 (Folder 149)
  - Current Issues in Higher Education serial monographs, 1973-1976 (Folder 150)
  - Literature of Higher Education, 1971 (Folder 150)
  - Service-learning in the Disciplines serial monographs published by AAHE, 1997-2000 (Folder 151-152)
  - Teaching Initiative, FFRR, and other published conference papers and programs, 1991-1999 (Folder 153-156)
  - Published papers from Working Papers series (New Pathways II project), 1996 (Folder 153-156)
  - The Literature of Higher Education, 1966-1967 (Folder 157)
  - Current Issues in Higher Education, 1971-1979 (Folder 157)
  - Lichtman, Jane. Bring your own bag: A report on free universities, 1973 (Folder 157)
  - Other monographs on higher education, 1980 (Folder 157)
  - Monographs from the Learning Climates that Cultivate Equal and Racial Diversity series, 2002 (Folder 158)
  - AAHE membership directory, 2003 (Folder 158)
  - Bowen, Howard Rothmann. Academic recollections. New York: Macmillan Pub. Co., 1988 (Folder 158)
  - Directories, programs, and other monographs relating to higher education in the United States, 1963-2003 (Folder 159-161)
- Incremental Materials, 1946-2005 (Box 162-166)
  Received in 2013
  - General records (Box 162)
    - General, 2003 (Box-folder 162: 1)
    - Organizational chart, 1999 (Box-folder 162: 2)
    - Constitution and bylaws, 1988 and undated (Box-folder 162: 3)
    - Logos and branding documents, 2004 (Box-folder 162: 4)
    - AAHE position statement on public accountability, undated (Box-folder 162: 5)
    - Writings
      - Untitled, undated (Box-folder 162: 6)
      - "The AHE Position, 1948-1965" by Tom Erhard, 1966 (Box-folder 162: 7)
      - "AAHE: A Learning Organization", 2002 (Box-folder 162: 8)
      - "The AAHE Plan", 2001 (Box-folder 162: 9)
      - Notes, circa 2002 (Box-folder 162: 10)
  - Presidential correspondence
    - Russell Edgerton, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 162: 11)
    - Clara Lovett, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 162: 12)
    - Clara Lovett, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 162: 13)
    - Clara Lovett - Closing of AAHE, 2005 (Box-folder 163: 1-4)
  - Meeting materials
    - Annual report of the executive director and business meeting reports, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 163: 5)
    - AAHE membership survey, 1999 (Box-folder 163: 6)
    - Board meeting, 1999 (Box-folder 163: 7)
    - Board meeting, 2000 (Box-folder 163: 8)
    - Board elections, 2001 (Box-folder 163: 9)
    - Board meeting, Spring, 2001 (Box-folder 163: 10)
    - Board meeting, Fall, 2001 (Box-folder 163: 11)
    - Board nominations information, 2004 (Box-folder 163: 12)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1981 October (Box-folder 163: 13)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 2002 October (Box-folder 163: 14)
    - Board of Directors meeting, Spring, 2003 (Box-folder 164: 1)
    - Board of Directors meeting, Fall, 2003 (Box-folder 164: 2)
    - Board of Directors meeting, Spring, 2004 (Box-folder 164: 3)
    - Board of Directors meeting, Fall, 2004 (Box-folder 164: 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting, Spring, 2005 (Box-folder 164: 5)
    - Executive Committee, 1979 (Box-folder 164: 6)
    - Executive Committee conference call, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 164: 7-8)
    - Members meeting, Washington State University, 2004 February 6 (Box-folder 164: 9)
    - Members meeting, Alabama, 2004 March 10 (Box-folder 164: 10)
    - Members meeting, Louisiana, 2004 March 11 (Box-folder 165: 1)
    - Members meeting, Tennessee, 2004 March 17 (Box-folder 165: 2)
    - Members meeting, Ohio, 2004 March 18 (Box-folder 165: 3)
    - Senior staff meeting agendas, 2003 (Box-folder 165: 4)
    - All staff meeting agendas, 2005 (Box-folder 165: 5)
    - Fellows meeting, 2004 April 12 (Box-folder 165: 7)
    - Lynton Professional service meeting, 1993 (Box-folder 165: 8)
  - Conference materials
    - National Conference on Veterans' Education, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 165: 9-11)
    - National Conference on Higher Education, resolutions, 1960 (Box-folder 165: 12)
    - National Conference on Higher Education, resolutions, 1961-1971 (Box-folder 166: 1-4)
    - National Conference on Higher Education, list of participants, 1971 (Box-folder 166: 5)
    - Black Issues in Higher Education, 2004 (Box-folder 166: 6)
  - Subject file. Dissolution of AAHE, financial and legal records, 2005 (Box-folder 166: 7)
  - Financial records, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 166: 8-9)
  - Printed matter. "Higher Learning and the World Crisis," address delivered at National Education Association of the United States meeting, 1948 (Box-folder 166: 10)
  - Miscellany, 1997-2005 (Box-folder 166: 11)